12th of March, 1937, San Juan is surrounded by soldiers.
About 20 Garifunas were killed and their homes and lands were taken by the dictator of Induras back then, Carias.
89 years later, San Juan is still surrounded, this time by 200 policemen from Induras.
And four, the Israeli-pact government of Nasri Asfura that is trying to steal more lands.
On July 6th, the Afro-Indigenous Garifunas community received an eviction.
So, a resort can be built on their ancestral land by the far-right government of Asfura.
And when they stood against the state, they were shot at, tear-gassed,
and at least five community leaders were kidnapped and detained by the state.
Land extrepriation, displacement, and settlement expansion is the Israeli core and blueprint.
Actually, after decades of trying to buy the Palestinian land from the Palestinian farmers,
alongside with the British mandate that was trying also to steal the lands and to create a legal umbrella,
for all of this, they only got less than 5% of the Palestinian land.
So, in 1948, they launched the barbaric, armed, Zionist troops that killed tens of thousands of Palestinians,
destroyed their lands and homes, and displaced a million Palestinians until now.
Building settlements, parks, and resorts over the stolen land,
and everything that is forming now what's so-called the genocidal state of Israel.
Between the land theft that is still happening here in Palestine, in Gaza Strip, and the West Bank by the Israeli settlers,
and the land theft happening to the Garifunas by the Israeli Enduran family,
we stand to ask, is it separate?
Is Palestine the only target for Zionism in the world?
And most importantly, what should we do?
Allah is ta'am.